

Ruhollah Taghizadeh

POSTDOC RESEARCHER

Department of Geosciences, University of Tübingen

☑ruhollah.taghizadeh-mehrjardi@mnf.uni-tuebingen.de | ☆ruhollahtaghizadeh.netlify.app | ☑RuhollahTaghizadeh | ☑RuhollahTaghizadeh | ☑RuhollahTaghiz

About me_

My primary research interest is in **Pedometrics** with a particular focus on **Digital Soil Mapping**. The core of the pedometric approach integrates soil system knowledge with **Machine Learning**, advanced statistical methods, **Geospatial Data Analysis**, and **Remote Sensing**. I apply the most recent technology in spatial data analysis to model and predict various environmental metrics such as soils, water, vegetation, and climate.

Experience	
Department of Geosciences, University of Tübingen, Germany Postdoc Researcher	2017-Present
Department of Plant Science, South Dakota State University, USA Postdoc Researcher (three months)	2016
Faculty of Agriculture, Ardakan University, Iran Assistant Professor	2013-2017
Department of Soil and Water, Agricultural Research Center, Iran Geospatial Consultant	2010-2011
Education	
Faculty of Agricultural Engineering and Technology, University of Tehran, Iran Doctor of Philosophy in Agricultural Engineering-Soil Science	2012
Sydney Institute of Agriculture, The University of Sydney, Australia Postgraduate Visiting Scholar in Digital Soil Mapping (six months)	2012
Faculty of Agricultural Engineering and Technology, University of Tehran, Iran Master of Science in Agricultural Engineering-Soil Science	2008
Faculty of Agriculture, SB University of Kerman, Iran Bachelor of Science in Agricultural Engineering-Soil Science	2005
Projects	
German Research Foundation Sensitivity and Response of Himalayan Timberline Ecotones to Global Warming (Collaborator)	2022
German Research Foundation Transferability of Machine Learning for Soil Mapping (Collaborator)	2020
Iranian Agricultural Research, Education & Extension Organization Digital Soil Mapping in Kurdistan (Collaborator)	2019
Alexander von Humboldt Foundation Digital Soil Mapping with Limited Data (Principal Investigator)	2017

Research Interests_

Pedology; Digital Soil Mapping, Remote and Proximal Sensing, Geographic Information System, Geospatial Data Analysis, Data Science, Machine Learning, Statistical Inference, Soil Health, Climate Change, Precision Agriculture

Teaching Assistant at University of Tübingen, Germany	2020-Present
- Spatial Pedology and Geomorphology	GS
- Statistics	UGS
Workshop Lecturer	
An introduction to Spatial Analysis in QGIS, University of Tübingen (two hours-online)	2022
An introduction to GIS, University of Tübingen (two hours-online) - Spatial Data Analysis in R, Iranian Soil & Water Research Institute (seven days-online)	2022 2022
- Digital Soil Mapping in R, Iranian Soil & Water Research Institute (two days)	2016
- Data Mining in Soil Sciences, Iranian Soil & Water Research Institute (two days)	2016
Fellowships, Honors, Awards	
Five Nominated Pedometrics Best Paper	2020
Alexander von Humboldt Postdoctoral Fellowship	2017
Lecturer Award at Ardakan University	2017
Professional Services	
Award Committee Member of the Pedometrics Commission	2022-Present
Executive Board Member of International Soil Modeling Consortium	2022-Presen
Associate Editor of Frontiers in Soil Science/Pedometrics	2022-Presen
Webmaster of Pedometrics Homepage	2022-Presen
Professional Training	
Data Scientist with R, DataCamp	2023
Open Source Solutions for Earth System Data, OpenGeoHub	2022
Oxford Machine Learning Summer School, AI for Global Goals	2022
Science Communication, University of Tübingen	2022
Agile Project Management for Research, University of Tübingen Spatial Sampling, Wageningen University & Research	2022 2022
Leading Virtual Teams, University of Tübingen	202.
Uncertainty Propagation in Spatial Modelling, Wageningen University & Research	2020
Geostatistics, Wageningen University & Research	2019
GEOSTAT Summer School, OpenGeoHub	2018
Digital Soil Mapping, ISRIC	2018
Digital Soil Mapping with R, The University of Sydney	2012
Technical Skills	
Programming - R	***
- R - R Markdown	
- Python	****
Spatial Data Analysis	
- QGIS	****
- ArcMap	****
- SAGA GIS	***
- Google Earth Engine	***
Statistics	<u> </u>
- JMP	***
- SPSS - Minitab	***
- MINITAD Microsoft Office	AAAX
MILE AD D'I	A-A-A-A-

- Word, Excel, PowerPoint

Field Work _____

Soil Sampling, Soil Survey, Geophysical Surveys, Soil Erosion Surveys	Iran
Soil Sampling, Soil Survey, Land Evaluation	Kenya
Soil Sampling	USA

Research Impacts

Publications Peer Reviewed Journals - First Author - Co-First Author - Last Author - Corresponding Author Book Chapters Book Editor (in Persian) Presentations	85 21 3 17 25 3 1
H-Index Google Scholar Scopus Web of Science	29 25 24
Citation Google Scholar Scopus Web of Science	2730 2045 1809

Publications

SELECTED PAPERS (* INDICATES CORRESPONDING AUTHOR)

- 1. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.***; Sheikhpour, R.; Zeraatpisheh, M.; Amirian-Chakan, A.; Toomanian, N.; Kerry, R.; Scholten, T. *Semi-Supervised Learning for the Spatial Extrapolation of Soil Information*. Geoderma 2022, 426, 116094, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2022.116094.
- 2. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.***; Schmidt, K.; Toomanian, N.; Heung, B.; Behrens, T.; Mosavi, A.; S. Band, S.; Amirian-Chakan, A.; Fathabadi, A.; Scholten, T. *Improving the Spatial Prediction of Soil Salinity in Arid Regions Using Wavelet Transformation and Support Vector Regression Models*. Geoderma 2021, 383, 114793, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2020.114793.
- 3. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.**; Hamzehpour, N.; Hassanzadeh, M.; Heung, B.; Ghebleh Goydaragh, M.; Schmidt, K.; Scholten, T. *Enhancing the Accuracy of Machine Learning Models Using the Super Learner Technique in Digital Soil Mapping*. Geoderma 2021, 399, 115108, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2021.115108.
- 4. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.***; Mahdianpari, M.; Mohammadimanesh, F.; Behrens, T.; Toomanian, N.; Scholten, T.; Schmidt, K. *Multi-Task Convolutional Neural Networks Outperformed Random Forest for Mapping Soil Particle Size Fractions in Central Iran*. Geoderma 2020, 376, 114552, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2020.114552.
- 5. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.***; Nabiollahi, K.; Minasny, B.; Triantafilis, J. *Comparing Data Mining Classifiers to Predict Spatial Distribution of USDA-Family Soil Groups in Baneh Region, Iran*. Geoderma 2015, 253–254, 67–77, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2015.04.008.

All Papers → Google Scholar and ResearchGate